（カブト）僕には　何もない。
I had nothing…
まだ…　まだ足りない。
This is still not enough…
これは…　まだ僕じゃない！
This is still not me!
だから　ずっと
付け足してきたんだ。
That's why…
I've kept adding onto myself.
That's why I don't need
your lectures.
欲しいのは
キミの説教じゃなく→
キミの能力と情報なんだよ。
I need your abilities and intel.
木ノ葉の忍であり→
Not only are you
a Leaf Shinobi,
有名な　うちはの血族であり→
you're of the famed
Uchiha bloodline.
万華鏡を開眼した
写輪眼を持ち→
You possess the Sharingan that
has awakened the Mangekyo…
多くの秘密を持って戦争を止め→
You bore many secrets
and stopped a war…
多くの術と力を持っていた。
You had many jutsu
and much power.
イタチ…　キミは　キミをキミたらしめる
多くのものを持っていた。
Itachi, you possessed many things
that made you who you are.
僕の穢土転生に
これ以上の適役はいないよ。
There is no finer Reanimation
out there of mine than you.
僕のコマは　僕の力そのものだ。
And my pawns are
part of my power!
（イタチ）買いかぶりだ。
You exaggerate…
現に俺は失敗した。
The reality is, I failed.
フン…　いや　さっきは→
No, even though I mocked
the Uchiha name in front of you earlier,
キミの前で　うちはの名をなどと
強がってはみても→
やはり　その名には羨望するよ。
I'm still quite envious
of that name.
うちはという名は
あくまで血統や所属を示す。
The Uchiha name merely
identifies one's bloodline
and clan membership.
お前が名乗ったところで
意味はない。
So it's meaningless for you
to claim it.
（カブト）僕は　何者でもなかった。
I was nobody.
（カブト）僕には　何もなかった。
I had nothing.
((あの町の子だろ？
I bet he's from that city…
この前　戦闘のあったとこだよ。
where that recent battle was!
（ノノウ）ご両親は？
Where are your parents?
心配しないで。　こう見えても→
Don't worry.
I may not look it, but I know
some Medical Ninjutsu.
医療忍術が　少しできるの。
カブト！　ってのはどうかしら？
How about…Kabuto?
雑！
適当！
Sounds simple.
That was quick.
You called it by just how he looks.
見たまんまじゃん。
（ノノウ）考えすぎないことが→
It's best not to overthink things.
(一番です))
（カブト）名をもらい
居場所が与えられるまで…。
Until I was given a name…
and a place to call home…
名乗ることに意味がない？
Claiming a name is meaningless?
いや　意味はあるのさ！
No… It does hold meaning.
Are you sure we can't kill him?
（サスケ）やつを殺したら
本当にダメなのか？
すべて　後手に回るぞ！
（イタチ）それはダメだと言ったはずだ。
We're stuck playing catch-up!
I told you no!
今は　やつが戦場を仕切っている。
耐えろ。
He controls the battlefield right now.
Be patient.
イザナミは　まだなのか？
仕掛けてくる気だぞ。
Is the Izanami still not ready?
He's about to come after us!
（イタチ）こちらも仕掛けている。
だが　もう少し時間がかかる。
I'm already on him.
It's just going to take
a little more time.
大蛇丸様は　こうも言ったよ。
Lord Orochimaru said thusly…
《カブト：左近　双魔の術！》
Sakon! Demon Twin Jutsu!
《カブト：次郎坊　土遁　土陸返し！》
Jirobo! Earth Style:
Terra Shield!
（カブト）自分が何者か知りたければ→
"If you want to know who
and what you are,
この世の　あらゆるものと情報
それらを→
"all you need to do is gather
every single thing
"and piece of information
that exists in this world!"
集めつくしさえすれば
いいってね！
《カブト：鬼童丸　蜘蛛巣開！》
Kidomaru!
Spiral Web!
この糸は　刀で切れない。
These threads can't be cut
with a blade!
– Amaterasu!
（サスケ／イタチ）天照！
《カブト：君麻呂…。
Kimimaro!
Macabre Bone Pulse!
Bracken Dance!
屍骨脈　早蕨の舞！》
後ろの奥まで
蜘蛛糸を仕掛けてやがったか。
He's laid down the spider silk
all the way to the back.
後ろは　俺がやる。
兄さんは前を。
I'll get the one behind us!
Take the front, Brother!
Can you still use the Susano'o?
まだ　スサノオは使えるか？
ああ！
Yeah.
Inferno Style! Flame Control!
炎遁　カグツチ！
（カブト）奥に逃げたか。
Running away to the back?
Well, it's no use!
でも　無駄だよ。
《多由也　魔笛夢幻音鎖》
Tayuya! Demon Flute:
Chains of Fantasia!
Are you okay, Sasu—?!
（イタチ）大丈夫か？　サス…。
A genjutsu, huh?
幻術か！
お得意のスサノオでも
音までは防げないよね　やっぱり。
Even your specialty, Susano'o,
cannot stifle sound…
I knew it…
これで動きは止めた。　あとは…。
Now you're immobilized.
All that's left is…
大蛇丸様で取り込むだけ！
to take you into me
using Lord Orochimaru!
The Izanami Activated
Well, Sasuke…
どうだい？　サスケ君。
覚えているかい？
Do you recognize
this current form of mine?
今のこの僕の姿を。
《あれは…》
That's…!
（カブト）キミが　大蛇丸様を
殺してくれたおかげで→
Thanks to you, I was finally
able to take
Lord Orochimaru into my body
after you killed him!
ついに　大蛇丸様すら僕の中に
取り込むことができたのさ！
そう　これが
今の僕の本当の姿！
Yes, this is my true form…
大蛇丸様の集め
研究しつくしてきた→
Remember, I said that all the laws
and principles of Nature,
which Lord Orochimaru researched
and compiled for so long…
自然界の法則　原理すべてが→
are now stored and
being used inside of me.
僕の中に
蓄積されてると言ったよね？
そこに足りなかったのは
この大蛇丸様自身！
The only thing that was missing…
was Lord Orochimaru himself!
今や　大蛇丸様すら
僕の中にある！
Now, I have him inside me!
キミには　感謝しても
しきれないくらいだよ　サスケ君！
I can't thank you enough, Sasuke!
カブト　お前は大蛇丸じゃない。
Kabuto…
You are not Orochimaru.
尊敬している存在を
真似るのはいい。
It's fine to imitate someone
you respect…
だが　その存在に
己を同一化するな。
But don't remake yourself
into him, to that extent.
人の多くは　何をするにも
まず　真似事から入るものだよ。
The majority of people start out
by mimicking someone.
サスケ君が　キミの真似を
していたように。
Like how Sasuke mimicked you.
((すげえよ　兄さん！
Wow, Brother!
岩の裏の死角の的にも
ど真ん中だ！
You nailed every target,
even the one in the blind spot
behind the rock!
よ～し　俺だって！
（イタチ）サスケ。
All right, my turn!
Sasuke!
そろそろ帰ろう。
It's time to go.
新しい手裏剣術を
教えてくれるって言っただろ。
You said that you would teach me
a new shuriken jutsu.
（イタチ）明日は
ちょっと大事な任務があって→
I have an important mission tomorrow
that I must prepare for.
その準備がある。
兄さんのウソつき。
You're a liar…
許せサスケ　また今度だ。
イテッ！
Sorry, Sasuke.
– Maybe some other time.
– Ow!
兄さん見てて！
Big Brother, watch this!
とう！
こら　ムチャしたら。
Hey!
Don't be reckless…
（フガク）この調子で　兄さんのように
立派にやりなさい。
Keep at it and become great
like your brother.
父さん　俺は…。
Father… I…
(さすが　俺の子だって
言ってほしかったんだ))
I wanted you to say that
you were proud of me.
その行為は
己が成長するための過程だ！
Such behavior is merely a process
to help one mature!
お前のように　己を偽るための
衣として使うな！
Don't use it as a cloak
to deceive yourself,
like you've done!
自分自身の値打ちを
称賛に値するものに結びつけ→
You gain nothing when
you attach your self-value
自分の存在意義を
見いだそうとしても→
to something external that's admirable
and praiseworthy to you.
そこには何もない。
最後に　もう一度言う。
I'll say this one last time.
ウソをついて　己をごまかすな。
Don't mislead yourself with lies.
己自身を認めてやることが
できないやつは　失敗する。
Those who cannot acknowledge
themselves will invariably fail.
（カブト）今の…　僕が失敗する？
Fail? The way I am now?
どうやって！？
How?!
サスケ　俺の眼を見ろ。
そういうことか。
Sasuke… Look into my eyes!
I understand!
幻術　写輪眼！
月読！
Genjutsu… Sharingan!
Tsukuyomi!
（イタチ）これより　イザナミに入る。
I shall now engage the Izanami.
お前はもう　失敗したんだ。
You have already…failed.
終わったのか？
Is it over?
すべてを持ってた天才には
わかりようがないよ。
A genius that had everything
would never understand…
僕は　僕を僕にしたいだけさ。
I just want to be who
and what I am!
誰にも邪魔させない！
I won't let anyone stop me.
サ…　スケ…。
Sa…suke…
《火遁　豪火球の術！》
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
《水遁　大瀑布の術！》
Water Style: Giant Waterfall!
（カブト）同じことを…。
さすがに手の内が読めるよ。
The same moves.
As expected…
It makes it easy for me to counter.
言ったはずだよ。
この体の回復力があるかぎり→
I already told you that as long as
I have my power of recovery,
手傷を負わせても無意味。
wounding me is meaningless.
視界を断った僕には
幻術は一切効かない。
Since I shut off my vision,
genjutsu won't work on me.
キミらに勝ち目はない。
You have no chance of winning.
お前の運命は
すでに俺に握られた。
Your fate is already in my hands.
それをなす　うちはの
もう一つの禁術　それが…。
Thanks to the Uchiha's other
Forbidden Jutsu.
That is…
なら　その運命　確かめてみたいね。
Well then…
Shall we put that to the test?!
イザナミだ！
…the Izanami!
サスケ　俺から離れるな。
Sasuke, do not leave my side.
まるで　デジャヴだね。
Why this is just like déjà vu.
もう飽きた。
I'm bored…
さっさと
この戦いを終わらせよう。
Let's end this fight already.
（イタチ）お前の運命を
握っているのは　俺だ。
Your fate may be in my hands now…
だが　お前の運命を決めるのは
お前自身だ。
but you're the only one
who can truly decide
how that fate shapes your destiny.
俺が言ったことを思い出せ。
Remember what I've told you.
そして　考えろ。
And think hard.
何を言ってるか
まるで　わからないね。
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
言葉遊びは　もういい。
Enough of your word games.
すべてを手に入れる僕こそ
本当の強者！
I will have everything…
I am the strongest of all!
それだけは　はっきりわかるよ！
That is fact!
己を許し　本当の自分を認める者。
He who forgives oneself,
who can acknowledge one's true self…
それこそが　本当の強者だ！
is the most powerful of all!
負け犬が…　ほざくな！！
Losers…
should be quiet!
《くっ…　これは…》
This is…
《これは　どういうことだ？》
What's…going on?
《なぜだ…　もうすでに
角は切られていたはず。
Why? That horn's already
been cut off!
どうやって…　視界は断っていた。
How? I have no sight…
どんな幻術にも
かかりようはない。
I should be invulnerable to genjutsu.
しかし　これは…》
But this is clearly a…!
僕に何をした。
What did you do to me?!
（イタチ）お前は俺の瞳術に　はまった。
You're in my Visual Jutsu.
ありえない！
Impossible!
It's the Izanami!
イザナミだ！
《どうやって…》
How…?
No matter.
いや　そんなことはどうでもいい。
この僕がやられるはずはない。
No one can stop me!
There's nothing I can't do!
僕に　できないことはない！
言ったはずだ。
I told you…
お前の運命は
俺が握っていると。
I hold your fate in my hands.
うちはイタチ～！！
Itachi Uchiha!
《これが幻術というのならば》
If this is a genjutsu…
解！
Release!
う～っ！
《落ち着け…　うちはの幻術。
Calm down…
This is an Uchiha Genjutsu.
Moreover, Itachi cast it,
so it won't be easy to undo.
それも　イタチのかけた術ならば→
簡単に破れるはずもない。
幻術破りなら他にも
方法はいくらでもある》
But there are many ways
to undo a genjutsu!
無駄だ。
俺の言ったことを思い返すんだ。
It's useless.
Recall my words to you.
ああ。　あんたたちの使った手を
真似させてもらうよ！
Sure! I'll copy the same trick
you two used!
多由也　夢幻音鎖！
Tayuya! Demon Flute:
Chains of Fantasia!
《これで　イタチの幻術支配から→
This will switch from Itachi's control
over genjutsu
多由也の幻術支配へと
移行すれば…》
to Tayuya's control.
う　うわっ！
ならば　こうだ！
Then, I'll do this!
Sage Art… Inorganic Animation!
仙法　無機転生！
この空間は　僕の支配下にある！
This area is under my control!
ここは　いったん退いて。
I'll retreat for now…
クッソ！　ふざけるな！
Damn it!
Don't mess with me!
やつは　この輪廻…。
He cannot escape
this samsara, this loop.
このループから
逃れることはできない。
これが…　イザナギと対になる
もうひとつの禁術…。
This is the other Forbidden Jutsu…
the companion to Izanagi.
運命を決める術…。
The jutsu that decides one's fate…
これが　イザナミだ。
This is the Izanami.
♪♪（太鼓）
（ナルト）『尾獣数え唄』
はじまり　はじまり！
Tailed Beast Counting Song!
All right, here we go!
♪♪「一つ　人より
居眠り守鶴」
One, "sleep is better than humans,"
says Shukaku
ONE TAIL SHUKAKU / GAARA
One, "sleep is better than humans,"
says Shukaku
♪♪「二つ　ファイヤー
燃えてる又旅」
Two, burning in fire, Matatabi
TWO TAILS MATATABI / YUGITO NI'I
♪♪「三つ　水なら
任せろ磯撫」
Three, leave the water to Isobu
THREE TAILS ISOBU / YAGURA
♪♪「四つ　溶岩
あついぜ孫悟空」
Four, hot as lava, Son Goku
FOUR TAILS SON GOKU / ROSHI
♪♪「五つ　いつでも
駆け足　穆王」
Five, always on the run, Kokuo
FIVE TAILS KOKUO / HAN
♪♪「六つ　無理せず」
Six, taking it easy and
not in a hurry, Saiken
SIX TAILS SAIKEN / UTAKATA
Six, taking it easy and
not in a hurry, Saiken
♪♪「アワてず犀犬」
♪♪「七つ　ナナフシ　空飛ぶ重明」
♪♪「八つ　やっぱり」
♪♪「ウィーだぜ　牛鬼」
♪♪「九つ　ココンと
最強　九喇嘛」
♪♪「とうとうそろった　尾獣の仲間」
♪♪「ちょい　ムズだけどいい名前」
♪♪「みんな　立派な名前だね」
♪♪「みんな　すてきな名前だね」
お次は　人柱力！
いくってばよ！
♪♪「一つ　ひどい
クマだよ我愛羅」
♪♪「二つ　フニャ～ンと　猫なでユギト」
♪♪「三つ　水影
四代目のやぐら」
♪♪「四つ　４０年　四尾と老紫」
♪♪「五つ　いかついパワーのハン」
♪♪「六つ　無口な
着流しウタカタ」
♪♪「七つ　なごむッス　くのいちフウ」
♪♪「八つ　やばいよ
ラップのキラービー」
♪♪「九つ　木ノ葉の
うずまきナルト」
♪♪「とっても強い　人柱力のみんな」
♪♪「尾獣と仲良くなれるかな？」
♪♪「みんな　立派な忍だね」
♪♪「みんな　すてきな忍だね」
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１０組の皆さんによる→